

# AARON C BARBER

CONTACT

+60 018 9850 469

AARON@AARONBARBER.US

W W W.AARONBARBER.US

## PROFILE

With over a decade of experience in the outdoor and cycling industry, I'm looking to provide my skills and knowledge to a company seeking to grow their business and marketing reach.

My passion for cycling and outdoor pursuits along with my skills in brand management fuel my drive to lead the industry's top product innovations and ideas into in the global marketplace.

## EXPERIENCE

#### OWNER/PROJECT MANAGER

54 PINES WEB DEVELOPMENT | MARCH 2016 - CURRENT

- Planned, designed and deployed digital marketing and web assets for businesses across multiple industries, including legal, hospitality, event marketing, print services
- Led development teams to complete 30+ web projects.

#### **BRAND SALES REPRESENTATIVE**

WSIOUTDOOR | DECEMBER 2009 - NOVEMBER 2016

- Managed 300+ accounts across 6 states in the southern United States.
- Delivered 1600+ product and sales presentations to buyers, floor staff and marketing coordinators detailing thousands of different product SKUs.
- Provided sales expertise and technical product knowledge for the following brands:

Arc'teryx | Smith Optics | Keen Footwear | REEF | Outdoor Tech | Salomon | Atomic Ski

#### GENERAL MANAGER AND MARKETING DIRECTOR

ADPEDAL/RDR | 2013-2015

 Managed company operations, a team of over 100+ contractors, and integrated marketing campaigns for the following brands:

Paypal | Captain Morgan | Formula One | Frito Lay | Keen | Nordstrom at the following events

Formula One | SXSW | ACL Fest | Moto GP | X Games | NFL and MLB Games

### EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATION
AUSTIN CODING ACADEMY | 2015
BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT, AUDIO ENGINEERING
LOUISIANA STATE UNIVERSITY | 2004

## SKILLS

- Excellent communication skills
- Confident negotiator
- Strong understanding of technical materials and manufacturing techniques
- Account management

- Proficient with MS Office Suite
- Capable in HTML, CSS, Javascript, along with Wordpress, Shopify, and various front end web frameworks
- Excellent time management
- Accomplished mountain and road cyclist.

## MEDIA

OUTDOOR TECH PRESENTATION FOR BIKEMAN4U - INTERBIKE 2015
PEDICAB EVENT MANAGEMENT - FORMULA 1 2014
ROCKSHAW LIVE! FEAT. LESS THAN JAKE - SXSW 2013